# Ei Pa Pa Pe-Than

eipa [at] cmu [dot] edu | <a href="https://eipapa.github.io/">https://eipapa.github.io/</a> | <a href="mailto:@eipa01">@eipa01</a> | <a href="mailto:Google Scholar">Google Scholar</a> | <a href="mailto:Research Gate">Research Gate</a> | <a href="mailto:GitHub">GitHub</a>

## **Research Interests and Approach**

My research interests span computer-supported cooperative work (CSCW), science and technologies studies (STS), and critical human-computer interaction (HCI), and especially how to develop distributive decentralized software systems to support productive cooperation, reinterpretability, resilience, and scalability.

I use Case Study research approach to address complex socio-technical questions, which includes ethnography (interviews and non-participant observations), archival analysis, quantitative collection of log and trace data with Python, SQL, and R, and a combination of all of these methods (mixed-methods) as appropriate and relevant.

## **Education**

| Carnegie Mellon U                              | University Pittsburgh, PA, USA   |
|--|--|
| 2017 - present                                 | Postdoctoral Researcher  |
|  | Advisor: James Herbsleb, Institute for Software Research, School of Computer Science   |
|  | Topic: Coordination in time-bounded events (hackathons, datathons, etc.) for science, innovation, learning, and civic engagement and collaborative writing on GitHub |
| Nanyang Technolo                               | ogical University Singapore, Singapore   |
| 2010 - 2016                                    | Doctor of Philosophy in Information Systems  |
|  | Advisor: Dion Hoe-Lian Goh and Chei Sian Lee, Wee Kim Wee School of Communication and Information  |
|  | Thesis: Investigating user-centered human computation games: The role of perceived enjoyment and its antecedents   |
| 2008 - 2009                                    | Master of Science in Information Systems   |
| University of Computer Studies Yangon, Myanmar |  |
| 2001 - 2005                                    | Bachelor of Science (Hons.) in Computer Science  |

## **Employment**

Carnegie Mellon University ...... Pittsburgh, PA, USA

2017 - present

**Postdoctoral Researcher** 

Advisor: James Herbsleb, Institute for Software Research, School of

Computer Science

Topic: Coordination in time-bounded events (hackathons, datathons, etc.) for science, innovation, learning, and civic engagement and collaborative writing

on GitHub

2015 - 2016 Research Associate and Part-time Lecturer

2009 - 2010 **Application Consultant** (Software Developer)

2005 - 2007 **Tutor** 

## **Research Funding**

NTU Doctoral Research scholarship

Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

Duration: August 2010 – August 2014

Amount: S\$ 111,600

Grant for Research Student

Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

Duration: 2011 – 2014 Amount: \$\$ 2,800

Conference Travel Grant

Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

Year: 2016

Amount: S\$ 1,000

### **Publications**

### **Referred Journal Publications**

1. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Nolte, A., Filippova, A., Bird, C., Scallen, S., and Herbsleb, J.D. "Corporate Hackathons, How and Why? A Multiple Case Study of Motivation, Project Proposal and Selection, Goal Setting, Coordination, and Project Continuation." [First round of revisions submitted to Human-Computer Interaction Journal]

- 2. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Dabbish, L., and Herbsleb, J.D. "Collaborative Writing at Scale: Investigation of Pull-Based Model on GitHub." [Under the review of CSCW 2020]
- 3. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Nolte, A., Filippova, A., Bird, C., Scallen, S., and Herbsleb, J.D. (2018). "Designing Corporate Hackathons with a Purpose." *IEEE Software, 36* (1), 15-22. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/asi.23863">https://doi.org/10.1002/asi.23863</a>
- 4. Nolte, A., **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Filippova, A., Bird, C., Scallen, S., and Herbsleb, J.D. (2018). "You Hacked and Now What?: Exploring Outcomes of a Corporate Hackathon." In *Proceedings of the ACM on Human Computer Interaction, 2* (CSCW'18), Article 129, 23 pages. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1145/3274398">https://doi.org/10.1145/3274398</a>

### **Referred Conference Publications**

1. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.** and Herbsleb, J.D. (2019). "Understanding Hackathons for Science: Collaboration, Affordances, and Outcomes." In *Taylor N., Christian-Lamb C., Martin M., Nardi B. (eds) Information in Contemporary Society, iConference'19. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol 11420 (iConference'19), pp. 27-37. Springer, Cham. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-15742-5">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-15742-5</a> 3* 

#### **Referred Short Publications**

1. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Dabbish, L., and Herbsleb, J.D. (2018). "Collaborative Writing on GitHub: A Case Study of a Book Project." In *Companion of the 2018 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW'18)*, pp. 305-308. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1145/3272973.3274083">https://doi.org/10.1145/3272973.3274083</a>

### **Referred Workshop Publications**

1. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Herbsleb, J.D., Nolte, A., Gerber, E., Fiore-Gartland, B., Chapman, B., Moser, A., and Wilkins-Diehr, N. (2018). "The 2nd Workshop on Hacking and Making at Time-Bounded Events: Current Trends and Next Steps in Research and Event Design." In *Extended Abstracts of the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems* (CHI EA'18), paper W35, 8 pages. https://doi.org/10.1145/3170427.3170615

### **Selected Other Publications**

- 1. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Momcheva, I., Tollerud, E., and Herbsleb, J.D. (2019). Hackathons for Science, How and Why? *Poster presented at the 233rd Meeting of the American Astronomical Society, AAS Meeting #233*, id.459.11. <a href="https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2019AAS...23345911P/abstract">https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2019AAS...23345911P/abstract</a>
- 2. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Dabbish, L., and Herbsleb, J.D. (2019). Collaborative Writing at Scale: A Case Study of Two Open-Text Projects Done on GitHub. *Paper presented at the 7th ACM*

- Conference on Collective Intelligence 2019 (CI'19). <a href="https://ci.acm.org/2019/assets/">https://ci.acm.org/2019/assets/</a> proceedings/CI 2019 paper 65.pdf
- 3. Powell, J., Hayden, L., Nolte, A., Herbsleb, J.D., **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Wong, M., Kalyanam, R., Ellet, K., Pamidighantam, S., Traxler, K., and Cannon, A. (2018). An Analysis of the PEARC 2018 Science Gateways Community Institute Hackathon: Lessons Learned. *Poster presented at Gateways 2018 organized by the Science Gateways Community Institute (SGCI)*. <a href="https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.7070309.v2">https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.7070309.v2</a>
- 4. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, and Nolte, A. (2018). The 2nd Workshop on Hacking and Making at Time-Bounded Events. *Technical Report CMU-ISR-18-109*, *Carnegie Mellon University*. <a href="http://eipapa.github.io/files/ISR-techreport-2018.pdf">http://eipapa.github.io/files/ISR-techreport-2018.pdf</a>
- 5. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Nolte, A., Filippova, A., Bird, C., Scallen, S. and Herbsleb, J.D. (2018). An Empirical Study of Team Familiarity, Goal Setting, and Process in Time-Bounded Events. *Poster presented at the 13th Annual Interdisciplinary Network for Group Research Conference (INGRoup'18).*
- 6. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Goh, D.H.-L., and Lee, C.S. (2017). "Does it matter how you play? The effects of collaboration and competition among players of human computation games." *Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology, 68* (8), 1823-1835. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/asi.23863">https://doi.org/10.1002/asi.23863</a>
- 7. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Goh, D. H.-L., and Lee, C.S. (2016). "Personality, motivations, and information quality: A comparative study across games for human computation." In *Proceedings of the Association for Information Science and Technology (ASIS&T'16), 53* (1), 1-10. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/pra2.2016.14505301049">https://doi.org/10.1002/pra2.2016.14505301049</a>
- 8. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Goh, D.H.-L., and Lee, C.S. (2015). "A typology of human computation games: An analysis and a review of current games." *Behaviour and Information Technology*, *34* (8), 809-824. https://doi.org/10.1080/0144929X.2013.862304
- 9. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Goh, D. H.-L., and Lee, C.S. (2015). "The effects of collaboration and competition on players' perceptions in human computation games." In *Proceedings of the 17th International Conference on Asia-Pacific Digital Libraries (ICADL'15)*, pp. 246-251, Springer International Publishing. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-27974-9 25
- 10. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Goh, D.H.-L., and Lee, C.S. (2014). "Making work fun: Investigating antecedents of perceived enjoyment in human computation games for information sharing." *Computers in Human Behavior, 39* (2014), 88-99. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chb.2014.06.023
- 11. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Goh, D. H.-L., and Lee, C.S. (2012). "Enjoyment of a mobile information sharing game: Perspectives from needs satisfaction and information quality." In *Proceedings of 14th International Conference on Asia-Pacific Digital Libraries (ICADL'12)*, pp. 126-135, Springer Berlin Heidelberg. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-34752-8\_16">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-34752-8\_16</a>

# **Teaching**

|                   | Nanyang Technological University, Singapore                                 |           |
|-------------------|---|-----------|
| Instructor        |   |           |
| CI6221            | Information Visualization (cross-listed, graduate)                          | 2016-2017 |
| CI6228            | Managing Information Systems (graduate)                                     | 2015-2016 |
| IN9008            | Digital Social Games for Organizations (undergraduate)                      | 2014-2015 |
| Teaching Assistan | t   |           |
| CS2008            | Fundamentals of Research (undergraduate)                                    | 2013-2014 |
| IN9006            | Social Computing and Applications (graduate)                                | 2013-2014 |
| CI6222            | Mobile & Ubiquitous Applications (graduate)                                 | 2012-2013 |
| CI6208            | Research Methods and Data Analysis for Information Professionals (graduate) | 2012-2013 |
|                   | University of Computer Studies, Yangon                                      |           |
| Tutor             |   |           |
|                   | Fundamentals of Data Structures (undergraduate)                             | 2006-2007 |
|                   | Operating Systems (undergraduate)   | 2006-2007 |

# **Professional Services**

# Reviewing

| 2020 | iConference<br>ECIS: European Conference on Information Systems<br>iConference   |
|------|--|
| 2019 | ACM CSCW: ACM Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work ECIS: European Conference on Information Systems iConference |
| 2018 | ACM CHI: ACM Conference on Computer-Human Interaction ECIS: European Conference on Information Systems iConference           |
| 2017 | ACM CHI: ACM Conference on Computer-Human Interaction Journal of Information Science Theory and Practice                     |

2016 Cyberpsychology, Behavior, and Social Networking

Aslib Journal of Information Management

**2015** ECIS: European Conference on Information Systems

### **Organizing**

2019 World of Code (WoC) hackathon, Carnegie Mellon University

2018 Science Gateways Hackathon by the Science Gateways Community Institute

(SGCI), PEARC18 Conference, Wyndham Grand Pittsburgh

ACM Workshop on Hacking and Making at Time-Bounded Events: Current Trends and Next Steps in Research and Event Design, ACM CHI'18,

Montreal, Canada

### Volunteering

2016 Student Volunteer, The 66th Annual Conference of the International

Communication Association (ICA)

2011-2013 Student Assistant, Graduate Admission Exercise, Wee Kee Wee School of

Communication and Information

2011 Student Volunteer, International Conference on Social Informatics

(SocInfo2011)

# **Professional Associations**

ACM Association for Computing Machinery

ACM SIGCHI Special Interest Group on Computer–Human Interaction

ACM SIGSOFT Special Interest Group on Software Engineering
ASIS&T Association for Information Science & Technology